(綱手)うん… では暁を
うかがわせる動きは➡
Then there were no developments
that would suggest
the Akatsuki organization.
存在しないと。
(アスマ)ええ。
That's right...
(アスマ)ですが 深刻な事態に
なることは間違いないでしょう。
However, there is probably
no doubting
that a serious situation will develop.
それは無惨なありさまでした。
It was a horrible sight...
(アスマ)一夜にして村が襲撃され➡
The village was attacked
in one night
多くの村人が亡くなっていました。
and most of the villagers were dead.
((雨隠れ…))
Hidden Rain...
その後 やはり国境線を
縫うように いくつかの村が…➡
And sure enough, as if weaving
along the border,
several other villages
were attacked after that.
すべて 火ノ国の村です。
They were all Land of Fire villages.
Asuma, don't rush to conclusions.
(綱手)アスマ 結論を急ぐな。
心得てますよ。
I understand that.
わざわざ雨隠れの印を残していく。
They go to the trouble of leaving
the Hidden Rain mark...
そのやり方も気にくわねえ！
I don't care for that approach at all!
戦争を
仕掛けたがっているヤツがいる。
Is there someone
who wants to start a war?
とも言えます… が そのもの
ズバリということもあります。
Perhaps... But sometimes
a guess hits the mark exactly.
雨隠れの動きで
何か情報はありませんか？
Is there no information on developments
with the Hidden Rain?
今のところは何も。
Nothing at this point.
(アスマ)しかし懸念すべきは…。
(綱手)火ノ国か？
But what we should be
concerned with is...
The Land of Fire, huh...?
ええ。 大名に…。
Yes...The Feudal Lord...
血気はやって大名を
あおるものがでるやもしれんか。
There might be someone
who recklessly instigates
the Feudal Lord, huh?
かつての守護忍十二士のように…。
Like with the Guardian
Shinobi Twelve before.
(綱手)武闘派のダンゾウに➡
The ammunition to intrude
in the situation
しゃしゃり
出てくる材料を与えかねんな…。
might be supplied to Danzo,
the old military faction leader.
一癖も二癖もある方ですからね…。
He's a sly customer to deal with,
after all.
暗部 ならびに里の上忍を割き➡
Assign some Anbu members
and village Jonin
and have them try to find some
information around the area of the border.
国境付近の情報を探らせる。
…が 現状がわからぬ今
極秘に行動させる。
But since we don't know
the present situation,
have them work in secrecy.
決して我が里から
アクションを起こさぬよう心得させよ。
And make sure they know
that our village is absolutely
not to stir up any action.
大名には
私から書簡を送っておこう。
I will send a letter
to the Feudal Lord.
Yes, ma'am.
(シズネ)はい！
アスマ班は➡
Team Asuma will move out
新たな動きが
入り次第動いてもらう。
the moment there are
any new developments.
Stand by until then.
それまでは待機！
わかりました。 では…。
Understood.
I will be leaving then...
Excuse me.
(ヤマト)失礼します。
守護忍十二士…。
The Guardian Shinobi Twelve...
Come to think of it,
Asuma was once...
そういえば かつてアスマさんも…。
Yeah. In those days when
he was a kid around twenty,
あぁ
ハタチかそこらのガキの時分には➡
火ノ国のため
なすべきことをなす！
he spewed some kind of
tongue-twister rationalization like...
なんて 舌を噛みそうな
理屈を さんざんぱら叩いて➡
"I'll do what I have to do
for the Land of Fire..."
三代目に噛みつき里を出て行った。
jumps down the Third Hokage's throat,
and leaves the village.
ま 私から見たら単なる親子ゲンカだ。
Well, from my standpoint,
it was just a simple father-son argument.
Uh-huh...
It happened ten years ago.
(綱手)それが10年前…
守護忍十二士の一部が➡
One part of the Guardian Shinobi Twelve
staged an unsuccessful coup
火ノ国を軍事大国とすべく
クーデター未遂事件を起こした。
in order to turn the Land of Fire
into a military superpower.
守護忍十二士は まっ二つに割れ➡
The Guardian Shinobi Twelve
were split right in two,
and Asuma and his comrades
brought that group down.
アスマと仲間たちは
その一派を壊滅させたのさ。
(ナルト)オッス アスマ先生！
Hi, Asuma Sensei!
Oh, Naruto. Are you making progress
with your training?
(アスマ)おう ナルト 修業進んだか？
Well, I actually
didn't have time for that.
いや それどころじゃ
なかったってばよ。
I see...
What're you doing here?
そうか。
何やってんだ？ こんなところで。
ヤマト隊長が
声かけるまで待ってろって。
Captain Yamato told us to
wait out here until he calls us.
(サクラ)ちょっと
何ガンたれてんのよ！
Hey! What're you doing glaring
like that?!
(ソラ)いや オレは…。
すみません もう 目つき悪くて。
Well, I...
I'm sorry he has such
mean-looking eyes...
Hey, you apologize, too!
ほら アンタも謝る！
Wh-Why do I have to...?
何で オレが…。
そんなことが あったんですか…。
So that's what happened?
And although they lost their lives,
(ヤマト)そのとき
命を落としながらも➡
クーデター一派を食い止めた
キタネ ナウマ トウウ セイト。
Kitane, Nauma, Tou'u and Seito
stopped the coup.
盗まれた ご遺骸は
彼らだったのです。
It was their bodies that were stolen.
なんだって!?
What did you say?!
申し訳ありません。 賊は４名。
I am very sorry.
There were four thieves...
and they were a group that used
quite advanced Earth Style Jutsu.
かなり高度な
土遁を駆使する輩たちでしたが…。
賊は ご遺骸を
どうする気なんでしょう？
What are they intending to
use the bodies for?
万一 彼らの中に眠る
貴重な術の情報が➡
Things will become problematic
should the precious Jutsu information
resting with them spread to other lands.
他国などに流れれば
やっかいなことになります。
う～ん…。
Yes...
Also, Sai was injured during the mission
and I had no choice
(ヤマト)それと 任務中 サイが負傷し➡
短期間ではありますが
離脱せざるをえなくなりました。
but to have him leave the team,
though it will only be for a short time.
そのかわりといっては なんですが
ともに任務に当たった➡
And as for his replacement
on Team Kakashi,
I would like to add
the young novice monk
火ノ寺の見習い僧の少年を
カカシ班に入れたいのですが…。
who was also
assigned to the mission.
But, well...
その…。
どうした？
What is it?
はぁ…。
Well...
Teammate
(綱手)なるほどな。
I see...
(綱手)では
その４人の墓荒らしどもは➡
So those four grave robbers were
lying in wait for each of you?
お前たちの いずれかを
待ち伏せていたと…。
(ヤマト)あの時点で いちばん
狙われる可能性が高かった➡
At that point in time,
I had Chiriku, the one they were
most likely targeting, leave the unit.
地陸さんには 隊から
離脱してもらったので➡
除外できるかと…
となると 暁同様 人柱力…。
So I think we can eliminate him.
In which case...
there's a slight chance that,
like the Akatsuki organization,
ナルトを狙ったという可能性も
ゼロではありませんが➡
they were targeting Naruto
who is a Jinchuriki.
我々が 火ノ寺へ派遣されたことは
たまたまですし…。
But it was a coincidence
that we were dispatched
to the Fire Temple.
(綱手)で 残るは その ソラ
という子というわけか…。
And so, that leaves that kid
called Sora, huh?
えぇ その場合 わが里において
行動をともにしたほうが➡
Yes. In which case,
I think it would be in our best interests
to have him in the village
working with us.
得策ではないかと。 もちろん
火ノ寺とも相談のうえです。
Of course, this is after consultation
with the Fire Temple.
Anyway, we're counting on you, Sora!
とにかく お願いよ！ ソラ。
綱手様の前では行儀よくしててね。
Behave yourself in front
of Lady Tsunade, okay?!
(サクラ)じゃないと
恐ろしいことになるんだから！
If you don't...
something terrible will happen.
そうだぞ 綱手のばあちゃんだけは
シャレきかねえんだからな！
That's right.
Witty remarks don't work
on Grandma Tsunade!
あぁ？ んなことで
オレが びびるかよ！
Huh? Is that
supposed to scare me?
火影だか ばあさんだか
知んねえけどよ➡
I don't know if she's an old lady
or a Hokage or what.
オレが拝んでやるぜ。
But I'll pay my respects!
(ヤマト)ナルト サクラ！
ソラ君を連れてきて。
Naruto! Sakura! Bring Sora in!
(サクラ)は… はい！ ほら 来て！
Y-Yes, sir.
- Okay, come on!
- Whoa...
(サクラ)それじゃ アスマ先生！
(ソラ)おい！
See you later, Asuma Sensei.
H-Hey?!
(サクラ)早く！ 失礼します！
Hurry up!
Excuse us.
(サクラ)綱手様!!
Lady Tsunade!
早く謝れ！
Hurry up and apologize!
There are great limits
to my patience!
仏の面は 一度っきりなんだよ！
誰が ばあさんだって!?
Who's an old lady?!
I called you a Buddhist saint!
菩薩さんって言いました！
(綱手)菩薩？
A Buddhist saint?!
Yes, yes!
かわいいこと言ってくれるねぇ。
この小坊主ちゃん。 合格！
Well, doesn't this little boy
say adorable things?
You pass!
(綱手)ようこそ 木ノ葉の里へ。
(ソラ)ちょっ… ちょっと！
Welcome to the Hidden Leaf Village.
H-Hey. That hurts...
《大きくなったな ソラ…》
You've sure grown up, Sora.
(ヤマト)じゃあ ボクは 報告書
作らないといけないから これで。
Okay, I have to write up a report,
so I'm off.
(サクラ)私も サイを
病院に連れていくわ。
I'll take Sai to the hospital.
(サイ)はい。
えっ… あっ…。
Okay...
Hey, wait a minute.
I need to continue with my training!
ちょっと待つってばよ！
オレも修業の続きを…。
なにが修業よ。 カカシ先生は
任務に出て留守じゃない。
Training, my foot. Kakashi Sensei's
out on a mission, right?
(サクラ)アンタは ソラに
里を案内してあげて。
You show Sora
around the village.
(サクラ)ソラは もう
カカシ班のチームメイトなんだからね。
Sora's now our teammate
on Team Kakashi.
冗談じゃねえってばよ！ なんで
こんな危ねえヤツなんかと…。
Heck no! Why do I have to be
with this obnoxious guy?!
オレだって こんな
罰当たり野郎と一緒なんて…！
I don't want to be with
this awful jerk, either.
(サクラ)はい はい！
そうやって二人で➡
Yeah, yeah.
You guys just go at it
as much as you like.
好きなだけ やってなさい。
もう のらないから。
I won't be joining in anymore.
Let's go, Sai.
(サクラ)行きましょ サイ。
(サイ)はい…。
Right...
(ヤマト)じゃあ ナルト。 ソラを頼んだよ。
Okay Naruto,
I'll leave Sora to you.
Y-You guys are dirty!
汚ねえぞ みんな！
(ソラ)はっ… ヤツらも同じか。
So they're the same, huh?
Huh?
結局 オレが やっかいなんだろう。
おい それ 違うぞ。
I'm just a burden, aren't I?
Hey, it's not like that.
サクラちゃんも ヤマト隊長も
やっかい者なんて思ってねえ。
Sakura and Captain Yamato
don't think you're a burden.
思ってたらな お前を 里へなんか
連れてきやしねえだろ！
If they did,
you wouldn't have been brought here
to this village, right?!
…わかってるよ。
I know that.
Then what is it?!
だったら…
お前 復讐なんて やめろよ。
Forget...about your revenge.
それとこれとは関係ねえだろ！
そうだけどよ…。
The two things aren't related!
I know, but...
(ソラ)父さんは
オレにとって ヒーローだった。
My dad was a hero to me.
心が強く たくましい人だった。
He was a courageous man with
a powerful inner strength.
(ソラ)５歳までの記憶しか
ねえけどな。
I only have memories of him
up until I was five.
火ノ寺のヤツらは
なんにも教えてくれなかった。
The people at the Fire Temple
never told me anything.
And yet, I happened to hear
about my dad being killed...
それでも 父さんが殺されたことは
オレの耳にも入った。
さげすむように 吐き捨てて…。
as they shouted in contempt...
(ソラ)自業自得だ
殺されて当然のことをした って！
"He got what he deserved!"
"Killing him was the right thing!"
My dad could never have
done anything devious!
(ソラ)父さんが
曲がったことをするはずねえ！
It must be some kind of mistake!
絶対 なんかの間違いだ!!
オレは ソイツを正す。 そして
そのうえで父さんを殺したヤツを…。
I'll rectify that...
And then after I've done that,
I'll get the guy who killed my dad!
お前…。
You...
(ソラ)だから オレに
まとわりつくんじゃねえよ！
So don't be following
me everywhere.
It's irritating!
うっとうしいぜ。
うっとうしいって…。
Irritating?
I'm showing concern for you
and that's your attitude?
心配すりゃ その態度か！
Huh? That's just called meddling!
フン！ それが
おせっかいってんだよ。
I'll feel out the enemy
on my own.
敵情視察は１人でやるぜ。
I'll take over this village...
in ten minutes!
こんな里
10分で しめてやっからよ。
お前は もう！
ったく… 勝手にしろ!!
Just do whatever you want!
オレだってな お前の相手なんか
したかねえっつうの！ フン!!
I don't want to deal with you, either!
What's he going to take over?
何をしめるっていうんだ？ アイツ…。
ったく… どこ
行っちまったんだってばよ？
For crying out loud, where'd he go?
えっ!?
やんのか!? コラ！
You want to fight, huh?!
I won't go easy on you just
because you're a dog, you awful jerk.
犬だからって容赦しねえぞ
このバチ当たりヤロウ！
(赤丸)ワン ワン！
赤丸に メンチかよ…。
He's glaring at Akamaru?
This is not good.
If Kiba shows up here...
まずいってばよ。
こんなとこに キバが現れたら…。
Oh, Naruto.
(キバ)おう！ ナルトじゃねえか。
帰ってたのか。
You're back?
Oh, Akamaru! There you are.
(キバ)おっ！ 赤丸。
こんな所にいたのか。
Who's he?
I haven't seen him before.
なんだ？ アイツ。 知らねえ顔だな。
Oh... he's...
あぁ… そのアイツは… あっ！
Hey, you! What're you trying
to do to Akamaru, huh?!
(キバ)おい テメエ！
赤丸に何しようってんだ？ あぁ!?
You're the owner?
テメエが飼い主か？
If you are,
then keep a leash on him
飼い主だったら
ちゃんと ヒモつけて➡
and train him not to bark
all of a sudden!
いきなり吠えねえように
しつけとけ！
Akamaru isn't a pet!
赤丸は ペットじゃねえ！ テメエが
怪しいから 赤丸が吠えたんだよ。
And he barked at you
because you're suspicious!
Where are you from?!
どこのもんだ!?
(赤丸)ワン ワン！
I'm from the Fire Temple.
火ノ寺のもんよ。
木ノ葉の里をしめにきたんだよ！
I've come to take over this village.
Huh?
はぁ？
ワンワン！
Sorry about this, Kiba.
I can explain.
いや～ わりいな キバ！
He's kind of with our team and...
コイツ ちょっと 訳あって
オレたちの班でさ…。
Naruto! Is he with you?
ナルト お前の連れか？
(ソラ)ふざけんな！
Knock it off! I'm not friends
or anything with this guy!
こんなヤツ ダチでもなんでもねえよ！
いいから お前は黙ってろ ソラ！
Just keep quiet, Sora!
Fighting's no good, you guys.
(チョウジ)ケンカはよくないな。 みんなさ
カリカリしないで 仲よく…。
Don't be so testy and let's get along.
Shut up, Fatty!
(ソラ)うっせぇ デブ！
D-Did you just say...
(チョウジ)い… 今 デブって言った…？
"Fatty"?
Yeah. So what of it?!
あぁ!? それが どうした？
(シカマル)ま… まずいぞ…。
しまった…。
Th-This is not good...
Uh oh...
(ソラ）よっしゃ！ バトルロイヤルだ!!
All right! Let's have a battle royale!
Hey, are you an idiot?!
って… バカか！
相手は テメエ１人だっつうの!!
You're the only opposition here!
Let's go, Choji!
(キバ)いくぞ チョウジ！
ヘッ！ そんなデブと 何ができる!?
Heh! What can you do
with a Fatty like that?!
You said, "Fatty," again, eh?!
また デブって言ったな…。
I'm not fat! I'm a chubby-type!
ボクはデブじゃない！ ポッチャリ系だ!!
わっ！ バカ やめろ!!
Whoa, you idiot! Cut it out!
All right! Keep a hold on him, Choji!
(キバ)よし！
そのまま捕まえてろ チョウジ!!
(ソラ)くっ！ きたねぇぞ オメエら!!
You guys are dirty!
Oh...! It's one against everyone?
あっ！ １人と全員かよ。
しゃあねえだろ。
It can't be helped. He asked for it.
ヤツがまいた種だぜ。
いや でも だからってよ…。
Uh, even so...
ああっ しようがねえ！
Ohh, I guess I have no choice!
Hey! Enough, already!
おい！ もう やめろって！
ナルト…！
Naruto! Are you taking his side?
コイツに味方しようってのかよ！
違うってばよ！
No, I'm not!
But I can't just sit here
and do nothing.
でも 黙って見てるわけにも
いかねえからな！
Huh? Why side with an outsider?!
(キバ)あん？ なんで よそ者に！
よそ者じゃねえんだよ コイツは！
I have no choice.
He's a Team Kakashi comrade, so...
カカシ班の仲間だからな！
仲間…。
Comrade...
So let's just calm down now and...
だから ここは
落ち着いて 話し合い…。
And let's discuss this...
ソラ！ お前のパンチが
当たってんだよ！
Hey! You're hitting me
with your punches!
You're the one who's been
hitting me with your kicks!
テメエの蹴りこそ さっきから…！
What?!
なにを…！
《バカか コイツら…》
Are these guys morons...?
イテエな こら…！
That hurts! Hey!
お前も加われなんて
言いっこなしっすよ。
You'll never get me to join in.
フッ… お前は
そんな ガラじゃないだろ。
Hah...That wouldn't suit you, right?
あんなのは ヤツらだけで十分だ。
It's enough to just
let them fight it out.
この里には もう１人いますね。
ん…？
Now we've got one more person
in this village, huh?
(リー)ぬおお～っ！
Why wasn't I invited to
(リー)夕やけ空で
男の友情を育む拳会議に➡
the "meeting of fists under a sunset sky
to develop the friendship of men?!"
なんで… ボクを
呼んでくれなかったんですか!?
(シカマル)ヤツら タフだから
いつまでも戦ってますよ。
They can fight forever
because they're tough.
ま そろそろかな。
えっ…？
Well, I guess
that's about enough.
Huh?!
獣人分身！
Man Beast Clone!
Leaf...
木ノ葉！
倍化の術！
Expansion Jutsu!
Shadow Clone...!
影分身！
風遁！
Wind Style!
- Uzumaki Barrage! - Beast Wave Palm!
- Severe Hurricane! - Human Boulder!
- Fang Over Fang!
(キバ)牙通牙…！
これは…！
What's this?!
ヘッ…！
(チョウジ)デブじゃな～い！
- I'm not fat!
- Oh!
Whoa.
(シカマル)うわ～っ！
(アスマ)こらっ！
Hey!
さてと 拳会議が終わったら
焼き肉で打ち上げだ！
Now then, let's have a party
at the Barbe-Q
after the "meeting of fists."
Barbe-Q!
(チョウジ)焼き肉！
(リー)いいですね！
That sounds good!
A dinner with tons of guys!
(リー)男だらけの食事会…！
結局それかよ…。
So after all's said and done
it's another party, huh?
行くだろ お前も？
You're going, too, right?
いや オレは別に…。
No, I don't particularly...
地陸は元気にやってるか？
How's Chiriku doing?
ああ そういえば アスマ先生ってば➡
Come to think of it,
I hear you're acquainted
with Chiriku, Asuma Sensei!
地陸さんと知り合いなんだってな。
(アスマ)ああ…。
Yeah...
オレの父さんも カズマって…。
M-My dad's name
was Kazuma and...
You've got some
pretty good moves.
(アスマ)お前さんの筋 悪くない。
ずいぶん 地陸に
もまれたんだろう。
Chiriku must've trained
you quite hard.
いや… 地陸様は 火ノ寺でも
偉い人だったから 自己流だよ。
No... Lord Chiriku was a great person
at the Fire Temple, you see.
It's my own style.
へぇ そうか。
１人で あそこまで…。
Oh, I see...
So you got that good by yourself.
Oh yeah! Hey, Asuma Sensei.
Show him that!
そうだ！ なぁ アスマ先生 コイツにも
あれ 見せてやってくれよ！
あれ？ うむ…。
That?
す… すげえ！
That's incredible...
The trick is to do it
steadily and sharply.
コツは 薄く鋭くだってばよ！
(アスマ)そうだ！
That's right!
そのコツを覚えたら
お前たちのクナイや手裏剣でも➡
Once you learn the trick,
you'll be able to send
your Kunai Knives and Shuriken
right through a tree trunk.
木の幹くらい
貫通させることもできるぞ！
じゃあな… がんばれよ！
See you around.
Good luck.
Hold on!
(ソラ)待ってくれよ！
If you know my father,
I want you to tell me about him.
(ソラ)父さんのこと…
知ってたら 教えてほしい…。
元守護忍十二士の…
カズマって名の！
He was a member of
the Guardian Shinobi Twelve
and his name was Kazuma...
Huh...?
なんで 殺されたのか…。
Why was he killed?
My father didn't do
anything wrong.
父さんは… 間違ったことは
やってない！
オレは そう信じて…！
That's what I believe...
知ってるよな!?
(アスマ)カズマは…。
You know him, don't you?!
Kazuma...
カズマは 信念を貫いて 死んだ。
Kazuma died sticking to
what he believed in.
それが どんな最期であっても…。
No matter how things ended,
ヤツは 自らが信じた
義のために死んだ。
he died for the honor
he himself believed in.
Oh...
じゃ 行くぜ。
Okay, I'm leaving...
H-Hey...
お おい…。
お前
今から修業しようってのかよ？
Are you going to do training now?
クソ…。
うお～！
Damn it...
お前には 負けねえってばよ！
I won't lose out to you!
One, two, three, four...
(フエン)ひい ふう みい よ…
ざっと30ぐらいかしら？
At a glance
it looks like about thirty...
(フドウ)あぁ そんなものか。
Yeah, around that many...
It's going to be quite different
this time around.
(フウカ)
今度は 今までと 訳が違うよ。
We're going to destroy
a village of the Kohaku Clan
火ノ国でも 有数の忍
琥珀一族の村を やるのよ。
with some of the greatest Shinobi
in the Land of Fire.
それも… きっちりと。
And...
一切を 殺す。
(フドウ)フフ… あぁ。
(フエン)わかってる。
前回までは 陽動 今回は…
いよいよ。
(フウカ)あっ 風属性の忍がいたら
教えてね。
ソイツは 私がいただくわ。
(フリド)お～い 琥珀一族の諸君！
死んじゃうんだぞ！
でも キミらの魂は 未来永劫
火ノ国を守る糧となる！
オレが 約束する！
ありがとう！
やれ。
よっしゃ！
勝つわよ！
はぁ…。
優勝したら 焼き肉一年分！
(ヤマト)違います！
今回は 木ノ葉崩し編からの➡
早押しクイズ！
木ノ葉崩しで➡
久しぶりに再結成した
旧いのしかちょうトリオ。
その１人 山中 イノイチの
得意技といえば？
心乱身の術。
(ヤマト)ですが… 奈良 シカクの
木ノ葉秘伝…。
影首縛りの術。
(ヤマト)ですが 秋道 チョウザの…。
超倍化の術。
(ヤマト)ですが… 里で暴れる➡
大蛇をしとめた
自来也様の術は？
そんなの知らねえってばよ。
私たち サスケ君を追いかけてたし…。
オレも 音のヤツらを
足止めしてたからな…。
ボク 寝てた。
(ヤマト)タイムアップ！ 正解は
口寄せ 屋台崩しの術でした。
ってことで 全員罰ゲーム！
(みんな)わぁ～！